(864)501-6630
COSTA.HUANG@OUTLOOK.COM
GITHUB.COM/VWXYZJN
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/COSTA-HUANG
WWW.COSTA.SH

Shengyi "Costa" Huang

SUMMARY

I am a PhD candidate at Drexel University working on deep reinforcement learning (RL), with a special focus on creating efficient algorithms and reproducible research. My advisor is Santiago Ontañón. I am the creator of CleanRL, a top 30 most popular deep RL library in the world.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Expected May 2023

B.S in Computer Science, B.S in Mathematics

Furman University, Greenville, SC

May 2018

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Intern

Riot Games, Los Angeles, CA

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

Deep Learning Algorithm Engineering Intern

NVIDIA, Santa Clara, CA

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

- Built better utilities in NVIDIA's Isaac Gym robotic simulation environment, which helps researchers to develop, test, and manage AI-based robots.
- Analyzed and benchmarked the performance of state-of-the-art deep RL frameworks such as Stable-baselines 3, rl_games, RLLib, and CleanRL, creating solid baselines for the research team.
- Implemented a more efficient multi-GPU training paradigm for rl_games that increased up to 20% more system throughput for training agents.
- Prototyped and delivered the integration between CleanRL and Isaac Gym, significantly lowering the barrier of entry to customize Isaac Gym for research.

Deep Learning Growth Engineer Intern

Weights and Biases, Palo Alto, CA

Jun 2021 - Sep 2021

- Authored a tutorial series on Proximal Policy Optimization popularized in the RL community, building the algorithm in PyTorch from scratch while covering 26 implementation details.
- Contributed the W&B visualization integration to popular RL projects, such as the MineRL competition (16k views) and Stable-baselines 3 library (used by 400+ packages).
- Created multiple ML educational content, including a blog post on AWS SageMaker and a webinar on experiment tracking and analysis workflow (200 + views on YouTube).
- Led the design and implementation of frontend features to improve experiment tracking and analysis workflow using React.js and TypeScript.

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Curai Health, Palo Alto, CA

 $Apr\ 2021-Jun\ 2021$

- Analyzed 4 years of experiment management needs in an AI-first healthcare startup.
- Surveyed 15+ state-of-the-art ML experiment management providers (e.g. Weights and Biases, ClearML, and Polyaxon), and led the technical discussion with these providers to tailor a solution.
- Implemented an experiment management pipeline that was adopted by the team's workflow, which covered dataset versioning, experiment orchestration, tracking, analysis, and tuning.
- Led the design of a prototype project to generate medical conversation by leveraging DialoGPT.

Graduate Research Assistant

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

PROJECTS

CleanRL

(github.com/vwxyzjn/cleanrl, 1.2k stars on GitHub)

High-quality single file implementation of Deep Reinforcement

Learning algorithms with research-friendly features

Python PyTorch OpenAI Gym Tensorboard Docker AWS
 Weights and Biases Deep Q-learning Policy Gradient Visualization

Gym-MicroRTS (github.com/vwxyzjn/gym-microrts, 100 stars on GitHub)

The OpenAI Gym wrapper of MicroRTS for deep RL research

 Python OpenAI Gym Policy Gradient Real-time Strategy Games Docker AWS Learning through Self-play CI/CD Numpy

Portwarden (github.com/vwxyzjn/portwarden, 372 stars on GitHub)

Create Encrypted Backups of Your Bitwarden Vault with Attachments

• Go Docker Kubernetes AES Encryption

PUBLICATIONS

Weng, J., Lin, M., **Huang, S.**, Liu, B., Makoviichuk, D., Makoviychuk, V., Liu, Z., Song, Y., Luo, T., Jiang, Y. and Xu, Z., 2022. EnvPool: A Highly Parallel Reinforcement Learning Environment Execution Engine, in review for NeurIPS 2022.

Huang, S., Kanervisto, A., Raffin, A., Wang, W., Ontan'on, S., & Dossa, R.F. A2C is a special case of PPO. preprint, 2022

Huang, S., Dossa, R., Raffin, A., Kanervisto, A., Wang, W. The 37 Implementation Details of Proximal Policy Optimization. *ICLR Blog Post Track*, 2022

Huang, S., Dossa, R., Ye, C., Braga, J., CleanRL: High-quality Single-file Implementations of Deep Reinforcement Learning Algorithms, accepted to *Journal of Machine Learning Research*, 2022

Huang, S., Ontañón, S., "A Closer Look at Invalid Action Masking in Policy Gradient Algorithms", *FLAIRS-35*, 2022

Compton, R., Valmianski, I., Deng, L., **Huang, C.**, Katariya, N., Amatriain, X., Kannan, A. MED-COD: A Medically-Accurate, Emotive, Diverse, and Controllable Dialog System. *Machine Learning for Health*, 2021.

Dossa, R., **Huang, S.**, Ontañón, S., Matsubara, T., "An Empirical Investigation of Early Stopping Optimizations in Proximal Policy Optimization", *IEEE Access*, 2021

Huang, S., Ontañón, S., Bamford, C., Grela, L., "Gym-μRTS: Toward Affordable Full Game Realtime Strategy Games Research with Deep Reinforcement Learning", *IEEE Conference on Games* 2021

Bamford, C., **Huang**, S., Lucas, S., "Griddly: A platform for AI research in games.", AAAI 2021 Reinforcement Learning in Games Workshop

Huang, S., Ontañón, S., "Action Guidance: Getting the Best of Training Agents with Sparse Rewards and Shaped Rewards", AIIDE 2020 Strategy Games Workshop

Huang, S., Healy, C., "StreetTraffic: a Library for Traffic Flow Data Collection and Analysis", poster presentation in *ACMSE 2018 Conference*

SKILLS

Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Numpy, Git, Linux, Statistics, Go, Docker, JavaScript, SQL.

RELEVANT COURSES

Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Computer Graphics, Algorithmic Game Theory, Software Design, Statistics, Probability, Linear Algebra, Real Analysis, Abstract Algebra, Fundamentals of Databases, Developing User Interfaces